

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Javascript
- Angular
- AngularJS
- ReactJS
- NodeJS / Express
- Socket.io
- Typescript
- Algolia
- HTML / CSS / SCSS / LESS / SASS
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- REST
- Python / Pytorch for ML
- Php

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS

- Git
- Jira
- Azure
- MongoDB Compass
- AWS
- SonarCloud
- Jenkins

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Reliable and professional
- Organised
- Efficient communicator
- Team player
- Fast learner
- Motivated
- Curious

LANGUAGES

- English
- Romanian

CONTACT

Phone: +40 730 799 252 Email: silviualexd@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/SilviuDinu

SILVIU DINU

ABOUT

Hi, I'm Silviu, a 27-year-old Full Stack Developer with over 3 years of experience in web development technologies such as React, Angular and NodeJS. Driven by curiosity, I'm constantly on the hunt for new projects that push my skill set further. Proactive and optimistic, I thrive when faced with challenges, always approaching them with a solution-oriented mindset.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

COGNIZANT, Bucharest I Oct. 2022 - Present

- As a Full Stack Developer in my current project, I not only engineer scalable
 and efficient software solutions, but also contribute strategic business ideas
 aimed at boosting customer revenue.
- Working with tools like: React, NodeJS, MongoDB, AEM, Algolia

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

EPAM SYSTEMS, Bucharest | Oct. 2021 - Oct. 2022

- Delivering top tier services for our clients.
- Working with tools like: AngularJS, Angular, NodeJS, Jira

CONSULTANT - MIDDLE FRONTEND DEVELOPER

DELOITTE DIGITAL, Bucharest I Feb. 2020 - Oct. 2021

- Actively engaged with our clients to ensure top-of-the-line services & consultancy through my work.
- Working with tools like: AngularJS, Angular, React, SCSS, Jira

JUNIOR PROGRAMMER - TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER

THEMEISLE, Bucharest I Jul. 2018 - Feb. 2020

- Aiding customers to build reliable WordPress websites
- Solving/reporting bugs and debugging (PHP, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL)

CERTIFICATIONS

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED - AZURE FUNDAMENTALS

18 Sep. 2023 View credential

MONGODB - SI ASSOCIATE CERTIFICATION

18 Jun. 2023 <u>View credential</u>

EDUCATION

MASTER'S DEGREE IN ADVANCED SIGNAL PROCESSING

Faculty of Automatic Control and Computer Science, University POLITEHNICA of Bucharest | 2020 - 2022

• Research work on how Machine Learning can help Medicine: <u>View on ReasearchGate</u>

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN SYSTEMS ENGINEERING

Faculty of Automatic Control and Computer Science, University POLITEHNICA of Bucharest \mid 2016 - 2020



PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Javascript
- Angular
- AngularJS
- ReactJS
- NodeJS / Express
- Socket.io
- Typescript
- MongoDB
- Algolia
- HTML / CSS / SCSS / LESS / SASS
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- REST
- Python / Pytorch for ML
- Php

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS

- Git
- Jira
- Azure
- MongoDB Compass
- AWS
- SonarCloud
- Jenkins

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Reliable and professional
- Organised
- Efficient communicator
- Team player
- Fast learner
- Motivated
- Curious

LANGUAGES

- English
- Romanian

CONTACT

Phone: +40 730 799 252 Email: silviualexd@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/SilviuDinu

PROJECTS / COURSES

RESUME / PRESENTATION WEBSITE

A presentation app built for myself containing information like: resume, who am I and what I do, hobbies and more.

Used tools: Angular 12, Angular Router, Angular Material, Typescript, RxJS https://silviualex.com/about-me

DISEASE PREDICTOR

I architected, fine-tuned, and validated a Neural Network that takes medical symptoms as input and forecasts the most likely corresponding disease. This model serves as the central element of a Flask-based backend server, which I also developed. This server is part of a custom API designed to interact with a frontend, accepting symptom data and returning the predicted disease.

Used tools: Python, PyTorch, Machine Learning, Flask, REST APIs, Data Science

REACT WEATHER APP

A weather app built with React and Express which enables the user to search the weather in certain cities around the world. The app automatically detects your location and displays the weather information that is most relevant to you.

Used tools: React Hooks, React router, Express, REST APIs, Typescript, MongoDB https://forecast-report.com/

WEB SOCKETS CHAT

A web chat application built with React on the FE and socket.io running on the BE. Users can connect to the chat room and exchange messages with each other.

Used tools: React Hooks, Node.JS, Websockets, Socket.io, Typescript https://github.com/SilviuDinu/web-sockets-chat

URL SHORTENER

A web app created with Vue.JS and Express that enables the users to create shortURLs.

Used tools: Vue.JS, Express, MongoDB https://slv.lol/